here's a beautiful visualization for the
alternating sum of squares starting with
n squared and ending at 1 squared N
squared can be represented by an N by n
array of boxes then we can remove the
lower n minus 1 by n minus 1 array
re-add the lower n minus 2 by n minus 2
array and so on all the way down until
we either add or subtract the bottom one
by one square array this process has
resulted in a collection of L-shaped
gnomons which we can shift together to
form a triangular array with base length
n this means that there are t sub n
boxes in the resulting array where T sub
n is the nth triangular number therefore
the alternating sum of squares starting
with n squared and ending at 1 is given
by n times n plus 1 over 2 by the
formula for the Triangular numbers